Adam Randall

www.adam-randall.tech Wellington 6012, New Zealand +64 27 631 0698

ajp.randall@gmail.com

Residency Status: British and New Zealand Citizen

PROFILE

Intermediate software developer with three and half years development and support within the Government sector and Telecommunications domain. AWS certified, with development skills in the Java and Ruby on Rails area. Exposure to all facets of development, from research analysis, project design, development, implementation and support. Key interests in a Dev-ops approach to development with automation and deployment to Cloud Services. Strong work ethic in terms of diligence, ownership and reliability. Friendly and approachable with the ability to work as part of a team or unsupervised. Able to acquire new skills quickly, and can adapt to new environments while building and maintaining excellent working relationships.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Datacom

Software Developer

Wellington, New Zealand Sep. 2012 – Feb. 2016

Discretion:

Discretion is an application to showcase security, messaging and collaboration features. It has two-factor authentication using physical U2F Keys and software authenticators. It allows two-way encrypted, end-to-end messaging with native apps, backed by Open Whispers Systems (Signal). It has two-way emailing, group messaging and the ability to secure image / video uploads. It also provides multi tiers of privacy and sensitivity of messages.

Discretion is a Ruby on Rails application that works in conjunction with a Java application. It relies on a number API calls, using callbacks to complete end-to-end transactions between the applications. It is backed by a Postgres database using Redis for background jobs. It required a lot of research and understanding of Open Whisper Systems libraries.

Gems Of Note: u2f, devise, devise_google_authenticator, devise_invitable, paperclip, interactor, foreman, pundit, mailgun-ruby, minitest, pry

Checkmate:

Checkmate was designed to enable Chorus (telecommunication) technicians to retrieve diagnostic information about a data line, whilst located at a customer location. It allows the technicians the ability to send a SMS code, to a designated number and receive relative information directly to their mobile.

This was a Java application that needed to be re-platformed to Ruby on Rails, with a number of additional features. It needed to handle both Web-Service and REST calls; with the ability to manage both incoming and outgoing SMS messages. This was developed using a test driven approach in a agile, iterative environment.

Gems Of Note: sidekiq, interactor, savon, foreman, bootstra, excon, kaminari, lograge, devise, devise_ldap_authenticatable, minitest, pry, ruby-oci8, activerecord-oracle_enhanced-adapter

Ministry of Justice Case Management System:

Ministry of Justice Case Management System is a Government application enabled to deliver Court and Tribunal services for Civil, Criminal, Family and Environment Courts. This includes the collection of fines and reparation, Court Rostering and Scheduling, Case Management and maintaining Coroners records.

It is a large complex legacy Java application, which requires regular legislative changes. It is the central block for the courts system, which provides several interfaces connecting the Police, Corrections and Collections to name a few. Development is undertaken with a waterfall approach, with strict time lines to meet legislative changes passed in Parliament.

Turbo Web

Web Developer

Dunedin, New Zealand

Nov. 2011 - Sep. 2012

An internship that turned into a part-time job while studying. The job provided creating web based solutions for clients, and improving businesses through online marketing. Websites were effective, efficient and to a high industry standard.

A number of projects were worked on involving front-end development, converting Photoshop mock-ups, back-end development. Technologies using Zend framework, Codelgniter, Magneto eCommerce and a internal MVC product.

University of Otago

IT Helpdesk Technician

Dunedin, New Zealand

Apr. 2011 - Sep. 2012

This was another part-time job while studying. It involved providing IT support for University staff members, solving problems daily (including P1 issues) and fixing technological problems when they arose.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Interpersonal Skills

- Friendly and approachable to clients
- Fast and efficient service
- Ability to deal with complaints and conflicts appropriately and effectively
- Ability to work well as part of a team or unsupervised
- Following instructions efficiently
- Relate well to others
- Reliable, courteous and well-presented professional demeanour
- Excellent computing and oral communication skills
- Dedicated work ethic
- Caring, attentive and always giving 100%
- Enthusiastic and outgoing

Experience

Development:

- Development in: Ruby on Rails, Java, JavaScript, JSP, jQuery, Spring Boot, HTML, CSS, VB6.0, Bootstrap, PostgresSQL, SQL, PL/SQL, Redis
- Technologies used: Ansible, Vagrant, AWS, Docker, GitHub / Subversion, CircleCl, Oracle 11g, SoapUl, Sublime, Toad / SQLDevloper / Datagrip (0xDBE), Intellij / Eclipse, Linux / Microsoft

Production Support:

Defect analysis from initial investigation to final solution.

- Day to day problem solving (using JIRA).
- Resolving Showstoppers (P1) / P2 Production issues.
- Solution verification and testing.
- 24/7 On-Call Support.
- Support of Development and Test Environments.

Test Support:

- Creating Mini-test suites, to run on CircleCl within Github.
- Supporting Test Team with Test Scripts.
- Providing Performance Reports of Environments.
- Creating Automated Test Scripts using Watir (Open Source Ruby Tool for Automation).
- Managing Automation of Test Scripts.

Other:

Wellington SVN Administrator

Technical Skill Levels

| Level: | | | | | | |
|--|----------|---|--------------|---|----------|--|
| Skill: HTML/CSS | Beginner | | Intermediate | | Advanced | |
| | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | | |
| PHP / MySQL / Adobe Photoshop | 1 | 1 | | | | |
| Oracle 11g / Toad / SQL Developer / WebLogic 11g | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | | |
| JavaScript / jQuery | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |
| PL/SQL - SQL | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | |
| VB6.0 / Shell Scripts | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |
| ASP.Net / JSP / Spring Boot | 1 | 1 | | | | |
| Subversion / Linux / Microsoft Systems | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | |
| Java / Eclipse / Oracle Reports Developer | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |
| Datagrip (OxDBE), Intellij, Sublime | 1 | 1 | 1 | 1 | | |
| AWS / GitHub / CircleCl / SoapUl | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |
| Spring MVC / Python / PowerShell | 1 | | | | | |
| Ruby On Rails / Docker / Spring Boot | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |
| PostgresSQL / Redis / Ansible | 1 | 1 | 1 | | | |

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified Developer Associate

Wellington, New Zealand 2015

Peoplecert

Wellington, New Zealand 2015

Oracle

Oracle PL/SQL Developer Certified Associate
Oracle Database 11g Administrator Certified Associate

Wellington, New Zealand 2014

EDUCATION

Otago Polytechnic

Bachelor in Information Technology Certificate in Information Service and Support Certificate in Network Administration Dunedin, New Zealand 2008–2012

INTERESTS

Sport:

- Involved in Rugby, Soccer, Basketball, Dragon Boating, and Soccer team
- Participated in multiple running events including Rotorua Full Marathon, and The Goat (22km hill climb around Mount Tongariro)
- Training for a charity event called IT Heavy Hitters, which is a boxing event to raise money for the Key of Life charitable trust'

Music:

• Formal training in Keyboard, Guitar and Drums

REFERENCES

Available on request.